Guide to the Dr. Robert King and Deena Barlev Holy Land stereoscope cards, 1896-1904 MS2243
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dr. Robert King and Deena Barlev Holy Land stereoscope cards
1896-1904
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
King, Robert, Dr.
MS2243
3 Linear Feet
This collection contains stereoscopic images of locations and scenes of the Holy Land and Palestine. The stereoscope cards date from 1896-1904. Several of the sets of stereoscopic images have descriptions of their subject printed on the back of the card, though some simply have a location or no additional information. A few of the stereoscope cards are numbered, corresponding to the book, Palestine through the Stereoscope, which provides a description and additional information.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. Robert King and Deena Barlev, 2007 (Accession 2007.074)
Biographical Note
Dr. Robert King, Deena Barlev, and their daughter, are all graduates of George Washington University.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains stereoscopic images of locations and scenes of the Holy Land and Palestine. The stereoscope cards date from 1896 to 1904. Several of the sets of stereoscopic images have descriptions of their subject printed on the back of the card, though some simply have a location or no additional information. A few of the stereoscope cards are numbered, corresponding to the book, Palestine through the Stereoscope, published by Underwood & Underwood, which provides a description and additional information. This book is shelved separately in Special Collections.
Nearly all of the images are copyrighted to Underwood & Underwood, a Kansas/New York City-based company founded by brothers Bert and Elmer Underwood in 1880. The company was bought by the Keystone View Company in the late 1910s.
Any oversized cards in the collection come from the series "Scenes of the Orient, 1882," created by Edward L. Wilson. These are more slightly more rare than the Underwood & Underwood cards.
Bib#
8286374
Middle East; Nineveh (Extinct city); Nazareth (Israel); Stereoscope; Description and travel; Palestine; Jerusalem; Western Wall (Jerusalem); Gaza Strip; Galilee (Israel); Dead Sea (Israel and Jordan); Bethlehem; Church of the Holy Sepulchre (Jerusalem); Damascus Gate (Jerusalem); Jordan River; Jaffa (Tel Aviv, Israel); King, Robert, Dr.; Underwood & Underwood
- Jerusalem, 1896-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jerusalem, 1896-1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Jerusalem, 1896-1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Jerusalem, 1896-1904 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Jerusalem, 1896-1904 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Jerusalem, 1896-1904 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Jerusalem, 1896-1904 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  General note
  Cards stored in a brown, leather book
- Ajalon-Bethany, 1896-1904 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Bethel-Bethlehem, 1896-1904 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Brook Cherith - Cypress, 1896-1904 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Damascus - Dotham, 1896-1904 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Elah - Garden of Gethsemane, 1896-1904 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Gethsemane - Gilboa, 1896-1904 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Haifa - Jacob's Well, 1896-1904 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Jaffa, 1896-1904 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Jezreel - Judea, 1896-1904 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Kedron - Moreh, 1896-1904 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Nazareth - Nineveh, 1896-1904 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Mt. Olives - Shiloh, 1896-1904 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Siloam - Tiberias, 1896-1904 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Misc., 1896-1904 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Misc. cards in this file are either too generic or too specific for useful alphabetizing.